
# Acts as a place to hold all riddles. its designed as a map of topic names to a list of maps each map containing a riddle and its answer

riddles = {
    "nature": [
        {"question": "I can fly without wings. I can cry without eyes. What am I?", "answer": "cloud"},
        {"question": "I have branches, yet I am not a tree. I have leaves, yet I am not a plant. What am I?", "answer": "book"},
        {"question": "I am tall when I am young, and short when I am old. What am I?", "answer": "candle"},
        {"question": "I flash across the sky and roar with power, yet I am neither man nor beast. What am I?", "answer": "thunder"},
        {"question": "I am water, but I disappear when the sun shines. What am I?", "answer": "dew"}
    ],
    "mythology": [
        {"question": "I am a king who flies too close to the sun and falls. Who am I?", "answer": "icarus"},
        {"question": "I have a head, a tail, but no body. What am I?", "answer": "hydra"},
        {"question": "I carry the world on my shoulders, but I’m not allowed to move. Who am I?", "answer": "atlas"},
        {"question": "My gaze turns men to stone, yet I am not a statue myself. Who am I?", "answer": "medusa"},
        {"question": "I am known as the trickster, god of fire, both friend and foe. Who am I?", "answer": "prometheus"}
    ],
    "star_wars": [
        {"question": "Though I am small, my power is great. I can lift starships with my mind. Who am I?", "answer": "yoda"},
        {"question": "I am An elegant weapon for a more civilized age. What am I?", "answer": "light saber"},
        {"question": "I once was a friend to the greatest of men, Now I hunt the rebels, time and again. My ship’s a bounty hunter’s best friend, I always complete my job to the end. Who am I?", "answer": "boba fett"},
        {"question": "Once a Jedi, now a darkened knight, My breath is heavy, my armor tight. I stand tall, with the Force in my hand, I wield a saber to rule the land. Who am I?", "answer": "darth vader"},
        {"question": "I’m small and I beep with joy, In battles and adventures, I deploy. Though not a human, I’m full of heart, A droid that’s been there from the start. Who am I?", "answer": "r2 d2"}
    ],
    "batman": [
        {"question": "A family walked in, but only sorrow followed, From grief and loss, a hero emerged, hollowed. Where am I, where the man behind the mask was born?", "answer": "crime alley"},
        {"question": "Once a sidekick, I met my end, But death could not hold me, I rose again. Now I carry guns, with vengeance to seek, Who am I, a hero turned dark and unique?", "answer": "red hood"},
        {"question": "I am the silent guardian of those who guard Gotham,A father to the fatherless, with wit as sharp as my resolve.I serve with tea and wisdom, but cross me, and you’ll taste steel. Who am I?", "answer": "alfred pennyworth"},
        {"question": "In the shadow of the Bat, I grew my wings, A bright young ward with acrobatic swings. I’ve had many names, but loyalty stays, A hero by night, in countless ways. Who am I?", "answer": "robin"},
        {"question": "In the darkest hours, I pierce the gloom, A light in the sky, where shadows loom. To the innocent, I’m a promise of aid, But to the guilty, I’m a fearsome blade. I shine not to guide, but to summon the night, A symbol of justice, in Gotham’s fight.What am I?", "answer": "the bat signal"}
    ],
    "spider_man": [
        {"question": "I’ve fought goblins, rhinos, and men with six arms, But still, I hold onto my human charms. I try to balance work and life as I can, But being a hero, I always take a stand. Who am I?", "answer": "spider-man"},
        {"question": "I’m a woman who’s dangerous and sly, I’m often on the wrong side, but I’ll never die. I can charm, I can fight, and I cross every line. Who am I?", "answer": "black cat"},
        {"question": "Once bonded with a man, I was cast aside, But when another came, our fates collided, With hunger and rage, I roam the streets, Not just for food, but for vengeance that never retreats. Who am I?", "answer": "venom"},
        {"question": "From the same bite that gave Spider-Man his might, I emerged in the shadows, hidden from sight. With webs and speed, I can swing and fight, But my past is my curse, and my future’s a fight. Who am I?", "answer": "silk"},
        {"question": "Though I was bitten, my journey’s not the same, With a new set of gifts, I’ll make my own name. From another world, but part of the crew, My role as Spider-Man, I must now pursue. Who am I?", "answer": "miles morales"}
    ],
    "transformers": [
        {"question": "I speak not a word, yet my heart roars, By my leader’s side, I’ve fought countless wars. Though small in stature, my courage is vast, My loyalty to the cause will always last. Who am I?", "answer": "bumblebee"},
        {"question": "I stand in the shadows, my voice never loud, But my loyalty is strong, I’ll stand proud. Cruel in my methods, yet true to my aim, I follow my leader, without shame. Who am I?", "answer": "soundwave"},
        {"question": "Born from the spark of valor, I stand tall, With a heart forged in honor, I answer the call. My path is one of sacrifice, and I never retreat, For freedom and justice, I’ll never accept defeat. Who am I?","answer": "optimus prime"},
        {"question": "I may not lead with a mighty sword or shield, But my intellect’s sharp, and I’ll never yield. From Cybertron’s depths, I rose to a grand fate, To defend my home and its fragile state. Who am I?", "answer": "perceptor"},
        {"question": "Through darkness and fire, I’ve carved my name, With a mind that plots and a soul full of blame. I seek to rise, to rebuild from the ruins, My enemies will fall, for they can’t halt my doing. Who am I?", "answer": "megatron"}
    ],
    "formula_1": [
        {"question": "On the track, I’ve set records anew, With a steely resolve and a drive that few knew. Seven titles I've claimed, but not just for the fame, In the hybrid era, I etched my name. Who am I?", "answer": "lewis hamilton"},
        {"question": "I danced in the rain and mastered the streets, Three crowns I claimed, my legacy still beats. In Monaco’s tight embrace, I reigned supreme, A hero in yellow, Brazil’s ultimate dream. Who am I?", "answer": "ayrton senna"},
        {"question": "From a legacy of racing, I rose to the sky, With speed unmatched, I took to the high. Youngest to lead, with records in hand, A champion in the making, now ruling the land. Who am I?", "answer": "max verstappen"},
        {"question": "In flames I fell, yet from the ashes I rose, A crash that shook the sport, but my spirit only grows. Survival in the heat, a testament to my might, I became a symbol of strength after that fateful night. Who am I?", "answer": "romain grosjean"},
        {"question": "Seven times I stood atop the world,In scarlet red, my legend unfurled.Through records broken, my name became might,A Rainmaster’s skill, and rivals’ fright. Who am I?", "answer": "michael schumacher"}
    ]
}
